Claudia Ruiz

Product Designer

in in/claudiaux

ClaudiaRuizUX

claudiaruizux.ga

@ClaudiaRuizUX

claudiaruizux@gmail.com

Sydney AEDT | Can Relocate

Hello, I am Claudia Ruiz and currently working as a product designer for a data company in the real estate and banking industries. With a background in graphic design, I moved to product design and now learning emerging technologies.

My experience (10y+) spans from startups to large organizations in the media and finance industries, using data to drive design decisions to balance the best level of quality with quick releases to continue the measure-improve cycle.

Through my time practicing design, I learned that building the right design case comes from a holistic understanding of people, technology, and systems. I stay fascinated by the interdisciplinary nature of the field, human factors, and emerging technology. Today my goal is to work with a very cool team on a meaningful project that supports decentralization.

Partners & Clients

















Claudia Ruiz

Product Designer

Experience

CoreLogic | Product Designer

Jun 2017 - Present | Sydney, Australia

Initially, I started working as a solo designer partnered with Pivotal Labs. We set up a Silicon Valley-style agile user research and the foundations for design across a variety of CoreLogic's products. I have been involved in repositioning the brand by designing complex greenfield products for the property valuation industry that helped our client to speed the loan process and secured investments throughout 2019-2020. Currently setting the foundation for the design systems.

The Link Group | UX Designer

Oct 2015 - Jun 2017 | Sydney, Australia

Designed and validated products workflows for a fund management system. We improved user flows and experiences so people engaged and connected better with their assets while making informed decisions.

The New Zealad Herald | Senior Product Designer

Feb 2011 - Sept 2015 | Auckland, New Zealand

I worked as a solo designer and developer supporting editorial. I created data visualizations for public accountability and interactives for storytelling that helped the user filter out the noise by focusing on the data. I won the recognition and award as the best innovation in New Zealand in 2012.

Moko Digital | Visual Designer & Developer

Nov 2009 - Dec 2010 | Auckland, New Zealand

I Interviewed customers to **understand their needs**, designed and developed solutions for their digital presence.

Trio Group | Multimedia Designer

Apr 2007 - Nov 2009 | Auckland, New Zealand

I designed sites to translate print content to digital media.

Languages

Spanish, Portuguese & English

- in in/claudiaux
- ClaudiaRuizUX
- claudiaruizux.ga
- 🄰 @ClaudiaRuizUX
- 🔁 claudiaruizux@gmail.com
- Sydney AEDT | Can Relocate

Education & Courses

Fundamentals of Bitcoin

Pomp's Crypto Academy | 2021

Foundations in Design Thinking

IDEO | 2020

Service Design

Academy Xi | 2020

Decentralised Experiences

Academy Xi | ConsenSys | 2019

Psychology (Single Subject)

Swinburne University | 2016

Design Systems

Nielsen Norman Group | 2016

UX & Research

Billy Blue College of Design | 2015

Diploma in Digital Media

(with distinction)

Media Design School | 2008 - 2010

Awards

Financial App of the year

MAX Awards | 2017

Best Innovation in Multimedia

Canon Media Award | 2012

Student Panel Board

Media Design School | 2011